#福建·福州
(Fuzhou, Fujian)
#你好
Hello
#一楼好像没有吃的地方
Doesn't look like there are any places to eat on the 1st floor
#进来了也没有人招待 也不知道朝哪儿走
No hostesses here either, not really sure which way to go
#应该是朝这边方向走
Should be in this direction
#看到了 看到了
I see it, I see it
#现在看到有人在吃饭了
Now I see that there's people eating
#应该是没错的
Should be this place
#还是没找到
(Still didn't find it)
#我问一下吧
Let me ask someone
#小哥 吃饭在哪边
Hey buddy, where's the restaurant?
#三楼
Third floor?
#哦 三楼
Oh... Third floor
#哎呀 好累呀
Aiya, it's so tiring
#这边是
These are...
#咱先说这个佛跳墙
Let's first talk about the "Fo Tiao Qiang"
("Buddha Jumps Over the Wall")
#最低
The cheapest one...
#是398 一位
is 398 yuan, for one person
#最高是金尊大坛正宗佛跳墙
The most expensive one is "Gold Supreme Large Jar" authentic Fo Tiao Qiang
#7980元 一坛
7980 yuan for one jar
#一大坛 当然这个是10人份的
A big jar, of course it serves ten
#咱不可能定这个预定版的 (最高金尊人均798元)
We won't order this reservation only one (Gold Supreme is about 798 a person)
#咱就要这种现成的
We'll order one that's already available
#要不就是398一位的 要不就是598一位的
It's either 398 each, or 598 each
#398的 是极品正宗佛跳墙
The 398 one is called "prime authentic Fo Tiao Qiang"
#还有一个是至尊正宗佛跳墙
The other one is "supreme authentic Fo Tiao Qiang"
#那个就是600块钱
That one costs 600 yuan
#其它的都是需要预定的 就不要了
All others are reservation only, so forget it
#价格也太贵了
And they're too expensive
#思考中
(Thinking)
#那我就要这个吧
I'll order this one
#398那个
The 398 one...
#极品正宗佛跳墙
"Prime authentic Fo Tiao Qiang"
#再加一个荔枝肉
And a "Lizhi Rou" ("Lychee Pork")
#再加一个芋泥吧
And also a mash taro
#佛跳墙一份, 对
One Fo Tiao Qiang? Yeah
#翡翠荔枝肉还是炸肉荔枝肉
Jade lychee pork or fried lychee pork?
#就是你刚才说的88块钱的
The one you said that was 88 yuan
#好,翡翠荔枝肉, 对
Ok, Jade Lychee pork. Yes.
#我也不知道它具体叫什么
I dunno what the name is either.
#它里面是加了马蹄是吧
It's got water chestnuts in it right? Yes.
#就是圆圆的一粒粒,吃起来比较脆那种
The round grain ones, crunchier kind.
#再要一个芋泥
All right. And a mash taro
#太极芋泥吗, 对
Tai chi mash taro? Yeah
#就这样吗, 够吃吗? 可以了
Anything else? Is that enough? Yes
#够吃 (够吃) 比较小
Enough (Enough) Smaller order
#量都比较小吗
Are the dishes small?
#对,佛跳墙它一份就这样子一碗吧
Yes, Fo Tiao Qiang 1 order is about this size per bowl
#试试吧 不够再加
I'll try this first. Will add if that's not enough
#好你可以先尝一下
Sure, have a try first
#酒水要吗
Anything to drink?
#不用要酒水, 好的
We're good (OK)
#咱们来的时候 首先是到一楼的大厅
When we came, we first came to the lobby on 1F
#但是它那个地方是没有卖饭的
However, there are no restaurants there
#只是有一个卖茶叶的
Only a tea store
#还有一个我不知道卖什么的
And another store selling I don't know what
#然后咱们是上了二楼 二楼有很多人在吃饭
Then we went to 2F, There's a lot of people eating there
#但是人家是保时捷销售和主管在这儿聚餐吃饭
However, those are salespersons, and probably managers of the Porsche dealership
#问了之后才知道
Then someone told me that
#原来吃饭的地方在三楼
the restaurant is on 3F
#我们真的是辗转反侧来到这个地方
That's quite a journey for us to get to this place
#费是...544, 可以
Excuse me, 544 in total. OK
#它这边是这样的
It's like...
#极品的佛跳墙是398
The prime Fo Tiao Qiang costs 398
#翡翠荔枝肉是88
Jade lychee pork costs 88
#香芋泥8块
Aromatic mash taro costs 8
#还有这边要收1%的服务费
And there's a 1% service charge
#账不对啊
(Wait it doesn't match)
#10%
10%
#嗯差不多
Hmm, that makes sense
#一落座 阿姨就倒来了茶水
Tea was served as soon as we were seated
#然后呢 给我们倒了一小碟的陈醋
And, we got this small plate of "chencu" aged vinegar
#作为调料品
as the seasoning
#还附赠了一小碟的甜品
And there's a complimentary dessert
#这里的服务真的是很到位
That's a very good service
#有一种在吃宴席的感觉
Feels like we are at a gala dinner
#每个人都是这种
Everyone here has like...
#红桌布上面再盖了一层（白）桌布
A red table cloth, on top of which there's a a white table cloth
#有的（人多）是这种大圆桌
Some (those with a lot of people) are big round tables
#像我们这种人少的 就是小方桌
And small square tables for small parties like us
#好 谢谢
OK, thank you
#这个是荔枝肉, 对翡翠荔枝肉
This is the lychee pork? Yes, jade lychee pork
#还是回到我们的佛跳墙
Let's go back to our Fo Tiao Qiang
#佛跳墙真的是不算大
The size is not big at all, for real
#这么一盅
For a jar like this...
#四百块钱
400 yuan
#上来佛跳墙 还配了一个银丝卷
The Fo Tiao Qiang is paired with a "yin si juan" ("silver thread roll")
#说和它配着来吃
to be eaten with the Fo Tiao Qiang
#现在
Now
#历史性的时刻开启
Let us witness this historic moment!
#好像除了一个蛋 都看不到什么东西
Other than an egg, I can hardly see anything
#里面的料太贵
The ingredients are really expensive
#里面有海参 鲍鱼这些 等等吧
It has sea cucumbers, abalones, etc.
#咱们就先喝汤
Let's taste the soup first
#避免这一碗吃不饱
Just in case we aren't full in the end,
#那咋办 不能再要一个吧
What do we do, can't really order another can we
#第一口你会觉得
On the first sip
#鲜中还带有点苦味
It's savory with a little bit of bitterness
#很神奇的味道
Quite an amazing flavor
#吃完这个佛跳墙 明天我就能重返18岁
After I finish this Fo Tiao Qiang, tomorrow I will be reborn as an 18 year old.
#大补啊
Mega panacea.
#这里面能够看到的
What you can see in here
#海参 鲍鱼 最大的鸽子蛋
Sea cucumber, abalone, the largest quail egg
#如果说你把（料）放进碗里
If you were to put them individually in a bowl,
#可能就是那么一小碗
It'd probably only fill a small bowl
#我在等有没有人帮我介绍一下
I'm waiting to see if someone can explain to me
#佛跳墙里有什么样的东西
What's actually in a fo tiao qiang
#有几样确实是不认识
There's a few things I really don't recognize
#你好 我想问一下 这个是什么东西 这个
Hello, may I ask, what is this? This one
#上面那个厚厚的东西吗
The thick thing on top?
#那个是鳖裙
That's calipash
#叫什么
What
#就是甲鱼的边
#壳周围的肉质软边
Basically the soft tissue underneath a turtle shell
#它里面还有一个
Ok there's another thing
#好像是有点带蹄筋似的东西
Looks tendon-like
#蹄筋就是蹄筋没错,就是像一个人字形的嘛
Tendon is correct, looks like the Chinese character "ren"
#猪蹄筋
Pork tendon
#还是一个就是花胶
And there is also fish maw
#花胶
Fish maw
#那类似粉丝的呢
What about the one that looks like rice noodles
#类似粉丝 这个是粉丝吗
Looks like a rice noodle, is this a rice noodle
#那个是鱼翅
That's a shark fin
#第一次知道这个, 长一点丝丝的是鱼翅
First time experiencing this. The longer strand-like one is shark fin
#短一点的一丝一丝的是瑶柱
The shorter strand-like ones are conpoy.
#瑶柱 就是大的干贝
Conpoy, they are large scallops
#谢谢
Thank you
#不客气 这里面一共9样食材
Your welcome, there are 9 core ingredients inside
#哦 9样食材
Oh, 9 core ingredients
#佛跳墙的汤颜色像中草药的颜色
Fo tiao qiang's soup color, looks like the color of Chinese medicine herbal soup.
#里面有九种食材, (极品正中佛跳墙有9种, 至尊正宗佛跳墙可能更多)
There are 9 core ingredients inside, (Prime fotiaoqiang has 9, Supreme probably has even more)
#它为了保持食材本来的味道
In order to preserve the flavors of the original core ingredients
#分别制成一道菜 然后汇集在一起
They prepare each one separately, then combine them at the end
#加入高汤和绍兴酒
Adding in soup stock, and shaoxing wine.
#再文火煨制十几个小时
Then simmer 10-20 hours
#才成了我们眼前的这一盅
To create the singular jar in front of us
#400块钱的佛跳墙
400 yuan... fotiaoqiang
#(喝汤)它虽然说是肉做的
(Drink soup) Though it's a meat based dish
#但是你品尝不出来任何油腻的感觉
There is no detectable oiliness/greasiness.
#我要告诉你 海参和鲍鱼是什么样的味道吗
Should I tell you what sea cucumber and abalone taste like
#说不出来的味道
Unexplainable
#每吃一口 都是钱的味道
Every bite, just tastes like money
#配这个吃也可以啊
It's OK to pair with this too
#这个可能就是接近8千块钱的佛跳墙
This is probably a fo tiao qiang that'll cost you nearly 8000 yuan